if three points are taken in two sides of a triangle...
如果三個點被採取 在三角形的兩邊
and the third side produced are in all three sides produced...
第三個邊減少 或者所有的三個邊減少...
so that the product of the three alternate segments taken in order -
以便提供三個選擇段被採取合理
Hi! Ouch!
嘿！嗷！
Hey, wait for me.
嘿！等一等！
I can't hardly move with all these creeper things.
這麼些藤蔓我真沒辦法弄掉
Them other kids must have got scattered in the dark.
其他的小孩一定已經在黑暗中被衝散了
We ought to go and find them.
我們必須去找到他們
My auntie told me not to run on account of my asthma.
我姨媽叫我別跑，因為我有氣喘病
- Asthma? - That's right.
- 氣喘病？ - 對呀
I was the only boy in our school that had asthma.
在我們學校就我一個男孩得氣喘病
And I've been wearing specs since I was three.
我還從三歲起就一直帶著眼鏡
- Where's the plane? - The storm must have dragged it out to sea.
- 飛機在哪裏？ - 暴風雨把飛機拖到海裏去了
There must have been some kids still in it.
機艙裏準保還有些小孩呢
Are there any grown-ups?
到底還有沒有大人呢？
- I don't think so. - What's your name?
- 我認為沒有 - 你叫什麼名字？
Ralph.
拉爾夫
I don't care what they call me...
我不在乎他們叫我啥名字
as long as they don't call me what they did at school.
只要他們別用在學校時常叫我的那個綽號
What's that?
那個什麼綽號？
- They used to call me "Piggy." - Piggy!
- 他們常叫我「豬崽子」 - 豬崽子！
As long as you don't tell the others.
只要你不告訴別人
Daddy's a commander in the navy.
爸爸是個海軍軍官
One day, when he gets leave, he'll come and rescue us.
他一休假就會來救咱們的
- Aren't you coming in? - Ooh, it's hot.
- 你不打算游泳嗎？ - 噢, 好熱
No. My auntie wouldn't let me - account of my asthma.
不，我姨媽不讓我這麼幹，因為我的氣喘病
Sucks to your asthma!
去你的氣喘病
You can't half swim well.
你游得不行啊
- Hey, look. - It's a shell.
- 嘿，看 - 一個貝殼
I've seen one like it before on someone's back wall.
我以前在人家的後屋牆上見過像這樣一個
A conch, he called it. He used to blow it, and then his mum would come.
那人叫它海螺。他常吹，一吹他媽媽就來了
He blew from down here.
他從下面這兒使勁吹
You've done it!
你做到了
Hey! Is anyone there?
嘿！那裏有人嗎？
Hey! Hey!
嘿！嘿！
I think we ought to go and explore a bit.
我認為我們應該去探一下險
- What's your name? - Percival Williams Madison...
- 你叫什麼名字？ - 珀西佛爾·威密斯·麥迪遜
the Vicarage, Hartcourt, St. Anthony.
哈考特·聖安東尼教區
Telephone: Hartcourt 241.
電話：哈考特 241.
- And what's your name? - George.
- 你叫什麼名字？ - 喬治
- What's your name? - Sam and Eric.
- 薩姆和埃裏克
Sam and Eric.
薩姆和埃裏克
Choir, halt!
合唱隊, 停!
Where's the man with the trumpet?
帶喇叭的大人在哪兒？
There's no man with a trumpet. Only me.
這兒沒有帶喇叭的大人，只有我
- Isn't there a man here? - No.
- 一個大人也沒有嗎？ - 沒有
Then we'll have to look after ourselves.
那麼我們只好自己料理自己的事情了
We're having a meeting. Come and join us.
我們在開會，過來參加吧
Is he all right?
他還行嗎？
Take him out of the sun. Put him in the shade, quick!
把他抬到陰涼的地方，快！
- All right. Let him alone. - But, Merridew -
- 好吧，讓他一個人待著 - 但是，梅瑞狄
He'll be all right. Simon's always throwing a faint.
他很快就沒事了，西蒙總是暈倒
Now let's decide what we're going to do.
現在讓我們決定我們該做點什麼
That's why Ralph made a meeting - so as we can decide what to do.
就為這，拉爾夫才召開這個會， 來決定我們該怎麼辦
We got most names.
我們已經曉得了一些名字
Those two - they're twins. Sam and Eric.
那兩個 - 他們是雙胞胎， 薩姆和埃裏克
- I'm Sam. - I'm Eric.
- 我是薩姆 - 我是埃裏克
I'm Ralph.
我叫拉爾夫
- And you? - Douglas.
- 您呢？ - 道格拉斯
Robin.
羅賓
- Yours? - Charles.
- 你的呢？ - 查爾斯
And what are all your names?
那麼你們的名字 ?
Henry.
亨利
Maurice.
莫裏斯
Robert.
羅伯特
Rupert.
魯伯特
Harold.
哈羅德
Bill.
比爾
Roger.
羅傑
- Simon. - I'm Jack.
- 西蒙 - 我叫傑克
- And that boy there. He - - You're talking too much.
- 那邊那個孩子，他—— - 你說的太多了
- Shut up, Fatty! - His name's not Fatty.
- 閉嘴，胖子 - 他可不叫胖子
- His real name's Piggy. - Piggy!
- 他真名叫豬崽子 - 豬崽子
We've got to decide about being rescued.
咱們該想想怎麼才能得救
I think we ought to have a chief to decide things.
我覺得該有個頭兒來對某些事情下決定
Yeah, someone must take charge.
必須有人負責
- I ought to be chief. - Him with the shell!
- 我要當頭頭 - 他有海螺！
- He got us together. - I'm chief chorister and head boy.
- 是他把我們集合到這裏的 - 我是合唱團的頭兒
Let's have a vote.
大夥兒投票表決
All right. We'll have a vote.
好的，我們投票
Who wants Jack for chief then?
誰要傑克當頭兒
- Who wants me? - Me!
- 誰要我當 - 我！
Me. Me.
我，我
I'm chief then.
那我當選頭頭了
Jack's in charge of the choir. What do you want them to be?
傑克負責合唱團，你們希望他們做什麼？
Hunters.
獵手
Choir, take off your togs.
合唱隊，脫掉你們的外套
Hey, what are you wearing those funny clothes for?
嗨，你們為什麼穿那些可笑的衣服？
It's our uniform.
這是我們的制服
Listen, everybody. If this isn't an island...
每個人給我聽著， 如果這裏不是一個島嶼
we might get rescued straightaway.
咱們可能馬上就會得救
So we've got to decide if it is.
所以咱們得決定這是不是一個島
Three of us will go on an expedition to find out.
我們將挑選三個人去探險
I'll go...
我去
and Jack.
還有傑克
- And - - Take me. Please.
- 還有 - 請帶上我
You. You all right now?
你，你還好嗎？
- I'll come. - We don't want you. Three's enough.
- 我也要去 - 我們用不著你，三個儘夠了
I was with him when he found the conch.
他剛找到海螺那陣子我就跟他在一起
before anyone else was.
我早就跟他在一塊兒，比誰都早
- You can't come. - You told them after what I said -
- 你不能來 - 你告訴了他們
after I said I didn't want -
我說了以後還告訴他們
What on earth are you talking about?
你到底在說什麼呀？
About being called Piggy.
關於稱呼我豬崽子的事
I said I didn't care as long as they didn't call me Piggy.
我說過只要他們不叫我豬崽子，別的我不在乎
And I said not to tell.
我還說別告訴人
And then you went and said straight out -
後來你就一下子說了出去
Better Piggy than Fatty.
叫你豬崽子總比胖子好
And anyway, I'm sorry if you feel like that.
不管怎樣，要是你感到不高興，我為此而抱歉
Go back, Piggy, and take names. That's your job. So long.
回去吧，豬崽子，去點名。 那是你的活兒，回頭見
Hey, look!
嘿，看
One, two, three.
一，二，三
Heave!
推！
We're on an uninhabited island.
我們在一個無人島上
We shall have to look after ourselves.
我們不得不自己照顧自己
But it's a good island. There's lots of fruit, water...
但這是一個很好的島嶼， 還有很多水果淡水
and I'm pretty sure there aren't any dangerous animals.
我敢肯定不會有任何危險動物
So things aren't so bad.
事情並不那麼壞
None of us are hurt.
我們沒有人受傷
There isn't any danger...
並無任何危險
and we can build shelters and be comfortable.
我們可以建很舒適的棚屋
So if we're sensible, if we do things properly...
如果我們很理智， 如果我們能合理地做事
if we don't lose our head, we'll be all right.
如果我們不迷失自我， 我們會過的很好的
- But where will we sleep? - We'll build shelters.
- 不過我們在哪裏睡覺？ - 我們會建棚屋
We can have smashing fun.
我們會玩得很開心的
And another thing. We can't have everybody talking at once.
還有件事，咱們不能許多人同時發言
We shall have to put our hands up, like we do at school.
必須像在學校裏那樣來個「舉手發言」
Then I'll give him the conch.
然後我給他海螺
I agree with Ralph. We've got to have rules and obey them.
我同意拉爾夫，咱們要做些規定並遵守
After all, we're not savages. We're English.
畢竟，我們不是野蠻人，我們是英格蘭人
And the English are best at everything.
英格蘭人做任何事都是最好的
So we'll have lots of rules, and when anybody breaks them -
因此我們將會有更多的規矩，當有人打破它們——
- Piggy, Piggy, Piggy! - Quiet!
- 豬崽子！豬崽子！豬崽子！ - 安靜
You're not letting Ralph get to the most important thing.
你們不讓拉爾夫說最重要的話嗎？
Who knows we're here?
誰知道我們在這裏？
Nobody knows we're here.
沒有人知道我們在這裏
Perhaps they knew where we were going to...
或許他們知道我們將要去哪裏
perhaps not.
或許不知道
But they don't know where we are now 'cause we never got there.
但是他們不知道我們現在在這裏，因為我們沒有到那兒
We might stay here till we die.
我們也許要待在這裏直到我們死去
He wants to know what you're going to do about the snake thing.
他想知道你打算怎麼處理關於蛇的事
Tell us about the snake thing.
告訴我們關於蛇的事
Now he says it was a beastie.
現在他說這是隻野獸
Beastie?
野獸？
- A snake thing, ever so big. He saw it. - When?
- 一個像蛇的東西，相當大。他看見那東西了 - 什麼時候？
When he was hiding in the jungle in the dark.
當他躲在黑暗的叢林中時
He says when the rain stopped...
他說是在雨停了時
it turned into one of them things like ropes in the trees...
它變成一個繩子一樣的東西，掛在樹上
and hung in the branches.
就掛在樹枝上
He says, "Will it come back tonight?"
他說：「夜裏它會回來嗎？」
But there isn't a beastie.
但是，這兒沒有野獸
I tell you, there isn't a beast.
我告訴你們，這兒沒有野獸
Ralph's right, of course.
拉爾夫是對的，確實
There isn't a snake thing, but if there was, we'd hunt and kill it.
沒有什麼蛇一樣的東西。 如果有，我們就抓住它，殺掉它
There's another thing.
還有件事
If a ship comes near the island, they may not notice us.
如果附近出船隻，他們無法注意到我們
So we must make smoke on top of the mountain. We must make a fire.
所以我們必須在山頂弄出煙來，我們需要生火
Come on! Follow me!
來，跟著我
- Yes! - Let's go now!
- 好 - 現在就走
Just like kids - like a crowd of kids.
真像小孩子————一群小孩子
I bet it's gone teatime.
我打賭是喫茶點的時候了
Anybody got any matches?
誰有火柴？
My, what a big heap you've made!
哎呀，你們搞了這麼個大堆！
Piggy's specs! Come on!
豬崽子的眼鏡，來！
Get out of the light!
站開，別擋光
Roger. Hey, Roger. Come on over here.
羅傑，嘿，羅傑。過來這裏
My specs!
我的眼鏡
Ralph, I'll split up my choir - my hunters, that is -
拉爾夫，我將把合唱隊————我的獵手們分開
and we'll be responsible for keeping the fire going.
我們負責看管生火堆的事
We'll make a big blaze now. It'll last all night.
我們會弄個大火堆的，它會持續一整晚
Come and give us a hand, will you?
過來幫幫忙
Attention!
立正！
Here comes one.
來一個
This is a nice one.
這個很好
Just a minute. Be careful.
等一下，小心
Go!
衝！
No!
不！
- You're gonna hit me, huh? - No, this isn't gonna hit you!
- 你要打我嗎？ - 不，這不會傷著你的
Ooh!
噢！
Come on, come on! Come on!
加油，加油，加油！
Kill! Kill! Kill!
殺！殺！殺！
No throwing sand!
別扔沙子
Ralph, come here! It's a plane!
拉爾夫，快來，一架飛機！
A plane! A plane!
飛機！飛機！
Can't you hear it? Ralph, it's going! Hurry up! Ralph!
你沒聽見嗎？拉爾夫，它走了，趕快，拉爾夫！
I can't see no smoke. Where is it?
我沒看見煙，在哪裏？
Smoke.
煙！
Piggy's glasses! If the fire's out, we'll need them!
豬崽子的眼鏡！要是火滅了，咱們用得上！
Stop! Come back! Come back!
停下！回來！回來！
Come back! Come back!
回來！回來！
They've let the bloody fire out!
他們讓火給滅了
Kill the pig! Slit her throat! Bash her in!
殺野豬喲！割喉嚨喲！狠狠揍喲！
Hey, Ralph!
嘿，拉爾夫！
Kill the pig! Slit her throat!
殺野豬喲！割喉嚨喲！
Bash her in!
殺野豬喲！割喉嚨喲！狠狠揍喲！
Kill the pig! Slit her throat! Bash her in! Kill the pig!
殺野豬喲！割喉嚨喲！狠狠揍喲！殺野豬喲！
Look. We killed a pig! We stole up on it. We got in a circle -
瞧，我們宰了頭豬，我們悄悄的撲上去， 組成一個包圍圈
You let the fire out.
你們讓火給滅了
We can light it up again.
我們可以再把它生起來
You should have been with us, Ralph.
你應該跟我們在一起，拉爾夫
There was lots of blood. You should have seen it.
流了好多血，你會看見的
There was a plane. There was a plane!
有過一架飛機，有飛機！
They might have seen us. We might have gone home!
他們本可能發現咱麼的，咱們說不定就可以回家了
You and your blood, Jack Merridew!
你和你們的鮮血，傑克梅瑞狄！
You and your hunting! We might have gone home!
你和你該死的打獵，我們也許都已經回家了
We needed meat.
咱們需要肉
You didn't ought to have let the fire go out!
你們不該把火弄滅了
My specs!
我的眼鏡
Here. Here they are.
這兒，在這兒呢
Just you wait!
你們等著瞧吧
That was a dirty trick.
真是個卑鄙的把戲
All right, all right. I'm sorry!
好吧，好吧，對不起
About the fire, I mean.
我意思是關於火
There.
好吧
I apologize.
我賠不是
Light the fire then.
點火
Choir!
合唱團！
- Piggy. - No, Ralph, don't! Please!
- 豬崽子 - 不, 拉爾夫, 請不要這樣！
I'll bring them back.
我會還給你的
- Will it swell up his legs? - Give me a nice piece!
- 腿會脹起來麼？ - 給我一塊好的
Give me a leg, will ya?
給我一隻腿
- Give it to me. - Give me a piece, please.
- 給我 - 請給我一塊
Aren't I havin' none?
我難道沒有麼？
You didn't hunt.
你沒打獵
No more did Ralph. No more did Simon.
拉爾夫也沒有，西蒙也沒有
Eat, damn you!
吃吧，該死的
- Kill the pig! - Oink, oink, oink, oink, oink, oink.
- 殺野豬喲！ - 呼嚕，呼嚕，呼嚕，呼嚕，呼嚕，呼嚕
Kill the pig! Slit her throat! Bash her in!
殺野豬喲！割喉嚨喲！狠狠揍喲！
Kill the pig! Slit her throat!
殺野豬喲！割喉嚨喲！
Quiet!
安靜！
Get down on the beach. I'm calling an assembly.
到海灘去，我要開會
Things are beginning to break up.
事情變糟了
I don't know why.
我不知道為什麼
It all began well.
開始時一切還好
Then people started forgetting what really matters.
不過現在人們開始忘了什麼最重要
The most important thing for all of us...
我們最重要的事
is getting rescued.
是得救
So now let's discuss who does what, and when we have decided...
現在我們需要討論誰幹什麼，在我們決定好之時
we can start again...
我們就可以重新開始了
and be careful about things like the fire.
對於火堆的事兒可得注意
All right, so the fire went out.
好了，也就是火滅了罷了
But we're hunters. We got you meat.
但我們是獵手，我們給你們肉吃
And if there is a beast...
並且如果有野獸
it's my hunters who will protect you from it.
我的獵手們會保護你們的
What's your name?
你叫什麼名字？
What's your name? What's your name?
你叫什麼？你叫什麼？
Quiet! Quiet!
安靜！安靜！
What's your name?
你叫什麼名字？
Percival Williams Madison, the Vicarage...
珀西佛爾·威密斯·麥迪遜
Hartcourt, St. Anthony.
哈考特·聖安東尼教區
Telephone -
電話——
Tele -
電——
Ready?
好了？
What did he say?
他了說什麼？
He says there's a beast.
他說有隻野獸
It comes out of the sea.
它從海裏來
My daddy said they haven't found all the animals in the sea.
爸爸說過，人們還沒有發現海中的說有動物呢
My daddy says there are animals -
我爸爸說那東西——
What do you call them?
你們叫它們什麼來著
They make ink and are hundreds of feet long...
它們會造出墨水來，有幾百碼長
and eat whales whole.
能吃下整條鯨魚
A squid can't come out of the water.
烏賊不會從水中跑出來的
Maybe he means it's some sort of ghost.
大概他指的是一種鬼魂
Maybe that's what the beast is - a ghost.
也許野獸就是————鬼魂
I don't believe in no ghosts. Ever.
我根本不相信有鬼，從來不信
Who cares what you believe, Fatty?
誰管你信不信————胖子
Maybe there is a beast.
也許真的有野獸
Hear him. He's got the conch.
聽他的，他有海螺
What I mean is...
我的意思是
maybe it's only us.
也許那只是我們自己
Nuts!
瘋子！
We should have left all this till daylight.
我們應該把所有事情留到天亮
We're tired.
我們都累了
We'll have a vote - on ghosts, I mean -
我們投票決定有沒有鬼
and then go back to the shelters.
然後回棚屋
Who thinks there may be ghosts?
誰認為也許有鬼魂？
- I see. - I didn't vote for no ghosts.
- 我知道了 - 我投票贊成沒有鬼
Remember that, all of you.
你們全都記住了
- You shut up, you fat slug! - I got the conch!
- 你住口，你這個胖懶蟲 - 我有海螺
Oh, Jack, let him speak. He's got the conch.
傑克，讓他說，他有海螺
And you shut up. Who are you anyway, just sitting there, telling people what to do?
你也閉嘴！不管怎樣，你算什麼東西？ 干坐在那兒————對人發號施令
- You can't hunt. You can't sing. - I'm chief. I was chosen.
- 你不會打獵，不會唱歌 - 我是頭頭，大家選我的
Why should choosing make any difference, telling people what to do?
選你又怎樣？只會發號施令
- Piggy's got the conch. - That's right. Favor Piggy as you always do.
- 豬崽子拿著海螺 - 對呀，你總是向著豬崽子
- Jack! - "Jack!" "Jack!"
- 傑克！ - 傑克！傑克！
- The rules. You're breaking the rules! - Who cares?
- 規則，你在破壞規則！ - 誰在乎？
Because the rules are the only thing we've got.
因為規則是我們所有的唯一東西
Bollocks to the rules! We're strong. We hunt.
讓規則見鬼去吧！我們是強有力的，我們會打獵
If there's a beast, we'll hunt it down and beat and beat!
要是有野獸，我們就把它打倒，揍了再揍
What's grown-ups going to say? Look at 'em!
大人們會怎麼說呢？瞧瞧他們那個模樣
I think I ought to give up being chief.
我感覺我應該放棄頭頭的位子了
You can't, Ralph. Not now.
你不能這樣，拉爾夫，現在不行
Blow the conch.
吹海螺
You've got to be tough. Make them do what you want.
你還拿著海螺呢，讓他們照你說的去做
If I blow the conch...
如果我吹海螺…
and they don't come back...
他們也不回來
then we've had it.
那咱們就自作自受了
Are there ghosts, Piggy? Or beasts?
有沒有鬼呢，豬崽子？有沒有野獸呢？
Of course there aren't.
當然沒嘍
- Why not? - Because things wouldn't make sense.
- 為什麼沒呢？ - 因為事情會講不通
Houses and streets...
房子啦、馬路啦
and TV.
電視啦
They wouldn't work.
那些東西不會起作用
But suppose they wouldn't make sense, not here on this island.
假如它們講不通？在這兒，在這個島上
Supposing things are watching us...
假如它們正在觀察著咱們
and waiting.
等著機會呢？
Go on being chief, Ralph.
繼續做頭頭，拉爾夫
- Who's there? - Me, Simon.
- 誰在那？ - 我，西蒙
I wish my auntie were here.
我姨媽在這兒就好了
Oh, what's the use?
那管什麼用？
Grown-ups know things.
大人懂事
They ain't afraid of the dark.
他們不怕黑暗
They'd meet and have tea and discuss.
他們聚會、喝茶、討論
Then things would be all right.
然後一切都會好的
- Sam. - What's the matter?
- 薩姆 - 怎麼了？
Shh!
噓！
- It was furry. - There was something moving...
- 它毛茸茸的 - 頭的後面
behind his head - wings.
有東西飄來飄去————翅膀
It sort of sat up.
它那麼直挺挺地坐起來
It had eyes...
有眼睛
teeth, claws.
牙齒，爪子
We ran as fast as we could, bashed into things.
我們倆沒命地奔跑
The beast followed us.
野獸跟著我們倆
Nearly caught me.
差一點抓住我
You're not pulling our legs, are you?
你們沒開玩笑吧，有麼？
- We'll hunt it. Who'll come? - Me! Me!
- 我們去抓住它，誰要去？ - 我！我！
But those sticks - they're made of wood. Don't be so silly.
那些長矛是用木頭做的，別傻了
- Frightened? - Of course I am. Who wouldn't be?
- 害怕了？ - 當然怕了，誰會不怕？
- Come on. Let's go. - Who'll mind the little ones?
- 來吧，我們走 - 誰來照顧小傢伙們？
- Piggy will look after them. - That's right. Keep Piggy out of danger.
- 豬崽子來照管他們 - 好呀，讓豬崽子別冒風險
Haven't you got any sense?
動動腦筋吧
How can Piggy help with only one eye?
豬崽子一隻眼能幹得了什麼？
Jack, is there anywhere on this island where we haven't been?
傑克，在島上你還有什麼地方沒去過？
There's only - Of course!
只有————當然囉
The tail end part, where the rocks pile up.
島的尾端，山巖都堆積起來的那個地方
I'm chief. I'll go on alone.
我是頭兒，我一個人去
The rest of you wait here and hide.
其他人待在這兒藏著
Do you think -
你是不是認為————
I've been all over. It must be here.
我到處都去過了，那東西准在這兒
I... don't believe in the beast.
我不相信有什麼野獸
I suppose not.
我猜也沒有
Couldn't let you do it on your own.
不能讓你獨個兒幹那
What a place for a fort!
這地方很適合做堡壘
The beast isn't here.
野獸不在這兒
Let's get the others and go on to the top.
我們去找其他人，然後去山頂
Now, this story is about the place where I live...
故事是關於我住的地方
called Camberley.
叫Camberley
Now, Camberley is quite an old place...
Camberley是一個很安靜很老的地方
but it hasn't been called Camberley all the time.
不過它不是一直被稱為Camberley的
It used to be called Cambridgetown.
它過去被稱為Cambridgetown
And they used to get mixed up with the letters...
人們總是把Cambridge和Cambridgetown
between Cambridge or Cambridgetown.
兩者搞混
So letters that were to a person in Cambridgetown...
所以寄往Cambridgetown的人的信件
used to go to a person in Cambridge.
常被送往了Cambridge
So they got a bit mixed up.
人們有點混亂了
So they thought they'd change the name at the post office...
所以他們想要改掉郵局上的名字
because it was the post office that had all the trouble of sorting the letters.
因為郵局需要排列信件
And they thought they'd leave the "cam" from Cambridgetown...
他們認為需要把Cambridgetown中的cam留下
and they -
然後他們——
and "ber" is a river...
「ber」指的是河
and there are a lot of rivers round there.
那兒周圍有很多條河
"Camber." And then "ley," because a lot of the towns near there ended with "ley."
「Camber」，然後加上了「ley」。 因為很多城鎮名都以「ley」結尾
Their names ended with "ley."
它們的名字以「ley」結尾
So they called it Cam-ber-ley. Camberley.
所以他們叫它Cam-ber-ley，Camberley
And that's the true story of Camberley.
這是Camberley的真實故事
I don't think we should leave Piggy with the little uns. Not all night.
咱們不能聽憑小傢伙單跟豬崽子在一起
We mustn't let anything happen to Piggy, must we?
我們不能讓豬崽子出什麼亂子，是不是？
I think someone should go back and tell them we won't be back till after dark.
得有人去告訴他們我們天黑以後才回去
I'll go. I don't mind.
我去，我不在乎
Honestly.
老實說
We'll go to the beach.
我們去海灘
We can go to the top tomorrow.
我們可以明天爬上山頂
If you're frightened, of course.
要是你嚇壞了，那當然
All right then. Who wants to go now?
好吧，誰想要現在就爬山？
You see?
你瞧？
I'm going to climb the mountain to look for the beast - now.
我打算上山去找野獸，現在就去
- Coming? - I don't mind.
- 你去嗎？ - 我不在乎
If you don't mind, of course.
要是你不在乎，那當然
Not at all!
我根本不在乎
I think it's silly only two of us go.
咱們真傻，為什麼就兩個人上呢？
If we meet anything on the other side, two won't be enough.
要是發現什麼東西，兩個人可不夠
All right. Come along, Roger.
好吧，走，羅傑
If you don't want to go on, I'll go myself.
要是你不想再上去了，我就一個人上
Go on then. We'll wait here.
那就去吧，我們在這兒等著
Shut up.
閉嘴
I saw a thing on top.
我看到山上有個東西
There was a noise too. Kind of "plop."
發出嘈雜聲，一種「噗噗」的響聲
Keep close to the ground.
貼近地面
Over there, gap in the rock.
那邊，被石頭擋住了
First, you know now we've seen the beast.
首先, 你們知道現在我們看見了野獸
We crawled up. We were only a few feet away.
我們爬過去了，我們在野獸幾英尺以外
The beast sat up and looked at us.
那野獸坐了起來看著我們
I don't think we could fight a thing that size. Honestly, you know.
我不認為我們能打敗它，老實說，你知道的
We're talk, but we couldn't fight a tiger.
我們談談，我們不能去攻擊老虎什麼的
We'd hide. Even Jack would hide.
咱們會躲起來，連傑克都會躲起來
- What about my hunters? - Boys armed with sticks?
- 我們的獵人怎麼樣？ - 那些拿木棒作武器的孩子們？
All right then.
好了，那麼
He's not a hunter. He'd never have got us meat.
他不是一個獵人， 他從來沒有為我們弄到肉
He's just giving orders, expects people to obey for nothing.
他只知發佈命令，想要大家遵守
He's like Piggy. He says things like Piggy.
他就像豬崽子，說話都像豬崽子
He's not a proper chief. He's a coward.
他不是個真正的頭頭，他是個孬種
On top, when Roger and me went on, he stayed back.
在山頂上，羅傑和我朝前的時候，他賴在後面
- I went too. - After.
- 我也上了！ - 那是後來
I went on too, then I went away. So did you.
我也上去了，後來我跑了，你也跑了
Call me a coward then. All this talk.
還叫我膽小鬼，扯淡
- All this talk, talk, talk. - Right.
- 這一切扯淡，扯淡，扯淡！ - 那好吧
I'm not gonna be part of Ralph's lot.
我不想跟拉爾夫同命運
I'm going off by myself to the rocks to hunt and have feasts and have fun.
我要獨自走開，去打獵吃肉，痛痛快快地玩
Anyone who wants can come too.
還有誰要走？
Jack!
傑克！
I said we could do without a certain person.
我說我們少一個人也能幹
Now I think we've got to decide.
我認為現在我們要下決心
We can do without Jack Merridew.
沒有傑克梅瑞狄咱們也能幹
There's others besides him on this island.
島上除了他還有別人呢
But now we've really got a beast -
但是現在我們真的發現了一隻野獸
though I can hardly believe it -
雖然我很難相信
we'll need to stay close to the platform.
咱們必須靠近平台待著
I've been talking, Ralph.
我一直在跟你說話，拉爾夫
What?
什麼？
We've got no fire on the mountain...
咱們山上的火堆是沒了
but what's wrong with a fire down here?
可是在下面這兒搞一個火堆又有什麼不好呢？
That's a good idea. We can build it right here between the shelters.
好主意，我們可以在棚屋之間築個火堆
I think we ought to climb the mountain.
我認為咱們該爬上山去
What's the use?
那又怎麼辦呢？
What else is there to do?
還有其他的什麼要做的？
And put some dry leaves on. Make sure they're dry.
放上些干葉子，確保他們是乾的
So it'll burn.
那才會燒著
If they're wet, it won't burn properly.
如果是潮濕的，就不會正常燃燒
Come on.
快
Now!
上！
Right up the ass.
正中屁股
Sharpen a stick at both ends.
弄一根木棒，把兩頭削尖
This head is for the beast.
這個豬頭是獻給野獸的
It's a gift.
豬頭是供品
Can't they see? Don't they understand?
難道他們就看不出？ 難道他們就不明白？
Unless we keep the smoke burning, we'll die.
沒有煙作信號，咱們就會死在這兒
What's wrong, Piggy?
怎麼了，豬崽子？
Why are things going wrong like they are?
為什麼事情會出錯？
I don't know, Ralph.
我不知道，拉爾夫
Looks like we're going to have a lot of rain, all right.
就要下傾盆大雨了
What about the fire?
火堆怎麼樣呢？
Hey, come back! That was a mean trick!
嘿，回來，這是個卑鄙詭計
We would have given it to you if you asked.
如果你要的話，我們會給你的
Take 'em some food.
給他們點吃的
Bananas!
香蕉！
Who'll join my tribe?
誰要加入我的部落？
Jack. I'll join your tribe, Jack.
傑克，我要加入你的部落，傑克
- Who'll join my tribe? - I want to join.
- 誰要加入我的部落？ - 我加入
I gave you food, and my hunters will protect you from the beast.
我給你們吃的，我的獵手們會保護你們免遭野獸的傷害
- Who'll join my tribe? - I will, Jack.
- 誰要加入我的部落？ - 我加入，傑克
I'm chief. And what about the fire? And I've got the conch!
我是頭頭，火堆怎麼樣？我有海螺
You haven't got it with you. You left it behind.
你沒帶著它，你把它丟在那兒沒有帶來
See? Clever.
明白些，放聰明點吧？
Anyway, the conch doesn't count on this end of the island.
海螺在島的這一頭不算數
The conch counts here and all over the island.
海螺在這個島的任何地方都算數
Who'll join my tribe?
誰要加入我的部落？
- Me, me! - I will!
- 我，我！ - 我加入！
- Let's join Jack's tribe! - Yeah!
- 讓我們加入傑克的部落！ - 耶！
Come away. There's going to be trouble.
走吧，會惹出麻煩的
Kill... the... beast!
殺野獸喲！
Kill the beast! Kill the pig!
殺野獸喲！殺野豬喲！
Slit her throat! Bash her in!
割喉嚨喲！狠狠揍喲！
Kill the beast!
殺野豬喲！割喉嚨喲！狠狠揍喲！
Kill the pig! Slit her throat! Bash her in!
殺野豬喲！
- Kill the pig!
- 殺野豬喲！
Kill the beast! Slit his throat! Bash it in!
殺野獸喲！割喉嚨喲！幹掉它喲！
Kill the beast! Slit his throat!
殺野獸喲！割喉嚨喲！
Look!
看！
The beast!
野獸！
Kill! Kill!
殺！殺！
Kill! Kill! Kill!
殺！殺！殺！
Piggy, are you the only one left?
豬崽子？剩下的就你一個？
There are some little uns.
還有幾個小傢伙
They don't count. No big uns?
他們不算數，沒大傢伙了？
Oh, Sam and Eric. They're collecting wood.
噢，薩姆和埃裏克，他們在拾柴火
- Nobody else? - Not that I know of.
- 沒有別人了嗎？ - 據我說知並沒有
Piggy.
豬崽子
- Piggy. - Huh?
- 豬崽子 - 嗯？
That was murder.
那是謀殺呀
You stop it! What good are you doing talking like that?
別說了！你老那樣嘮叨有什麼好處？
It was dark! There was that bloody dance!
那時天昏地暗，加上那該死的狂舞
There was thunder and lightning and rain!
又是閃電，又是霹靂，又是暴雨
We were scared!
咱們全嚇壞了
It wasn't... what you said.
那可不是——像你說的那樣
Oh, Piggy!
哦，豬崽子！
It was an accident.
這是意外
He was batty.
他瘋了
He asked for it. It was an accident.
他自找的，這是一次意外
Oh, God, I want to go home.
哦，上帝啊，我要回家
Take him away!
把他帶走
Tomorrow, I'll hunt again.
明天，我們又要去打獵了
Then we'll leave another head for the beast.
我們需要另一個豬頭獻給怪獸
Some of you will stay and defend the gate.
你們留下一些人看守這裏
The beast may try and come in.
野獸也想要進來
Remember how he crawled?
記得它是怎麼爬的吧
He came disguised.
它化了裝來的
The beast may try and come...
野獸會嘗試著混進來
even though we gave him the head of our kill to eat.
即使咱們殺了豬，把豬頭給它吃
So watch and be careful.
所以得提防著，得當心點
But didn't we - Didn't we -
但是咱們能不能，能不能——？
No. How could we kill it?
不，咱們怎麼能殺掉它呢？
He told us. The beast was disguised.
他告訴我們，野獸是會偽裝的
Tomorrow, when we get meat, we'll have a feast.
明天我們將去打獵，然後大吃一頓
- Chief? - Yes, Bill?
- 頭領 - 嗯？比爾
What'll we use to light the fire?
咱們用什麼來生火呢？
We'll get fire from the others.
我們將從別人那兒去取火種來
We've got to get out of this.
咱們一定得擺脫這個地方
What do you mean?
這話怎麼講？
Get rescued.
要得救
I mean it.
這就是我的意思
If we don't get out of here soon, we'll be barmy.
要不趕快回家，咱們都會發瘋
- Round the bend. - Crackers.
- 神經錯亂 - 發狂
Have you written a letter to your auntie lately?
你最近給你姨媽寫信了麼？
I don't know where she is now...
我不知道眼下她在哪兒
and I haven't got an envelope or a stamp...
我沒有信封，沒有郵票
and there isn't a pillar-box or a postman.
再說既沒有郵箱，也沒有郵遞員
I haven't said anything very funny.
我可沒說什麼，有那麼好笑
Piggy-y-y-y!
豬崽子！
Don't make a sound.
別吱聲
We're going to get you, Piggy.
我們來找你了，豬崽子
Piggy?
豬崽子？
Where are you, Piggy?
你在哪兒？豬崽子？
We've come to get you.
我們來找你了
Piggy, you've changed!
豬崽子，你變樣了
Piggy!
豬崽子
I just take the conch to say this.
我拿著海螺
I can't see without my glasses...
我沒有眼鏡就看不見東西
and I got to get them back.
我必須得要回我的眼鏡
What are we going to do?
我們要去幹什麼？
Hey! Who goes there?
是誰在那兒？
Stop being silly! You can see who I am!
別裝傻了，你認得出我是誰！
I'm calling an assembly!
我要開大會
Don't leave me, Ralph!
別離開我，拉爾夫！
You sit down and wait for me. Here.
你坐下，在這兒等我回來
What do you want?
你們要幹什麼？
Go away, Ralph. You keep to your end.
你們滾開，拉爾夫。你們守著你們那一頭
This is my end and my tribe. You have to leave me alone.
這兒是我的一頭，我的一夥人，你們別來管我
You took Piggy's specs. You've got to give them back.
你搶走了豬崽子的眼鏡，你一定得還給他
Got to? Who says?
一定得？誰說的？
I say! That was a dirty trick.
我說的！那是一個骯髒把戲
We would have given you fire if you asked for it.
你要火種我們本來是會給你們的
But you didn't. You came sneaking up like a thief.
可你不是來要，你像個賊似的偷偷地跑來
- Say that again. - Thief! Thief!
- 你再說一遍 - 賊！賊！
Who's a thief?
誰是賊？
You are!
你是
Ralph! Remember what we came for.
拉爾夫，記得我們來的目的
The fire. My specs.
火種，我的眼鏡
Don't you see? There may be a ship out there or a plane!
你們不明白嗎？或許有船或飛機經過
- Grab 'em! - Jack!
- 抓住他們 - 傑克
Tie 'em up!
綁住他們
See? They do what I want.
看見嗎？他們聽我的吩咐
You're a beast and a swine and a bloody, bloody thief!
你是野獸，是豬玀，是個地地道道的賊
Go, Jack! Go!
上，傑克，上
Let me speak!
讓我說話
I've got the conch!
我拿著海螺
Which is it better to be?
哪一個好一些？
A pack of painted savages like you are...
是像你們那樣做一幫塗臉的黑鬼好呢？
or sensible like Ralph is?
還是像拉爾夫那樣做一個明白事理的人好呢？
Which is better?
哪一個好一些？
To have rules and agree, or to hunt and kill?
是照規則、講一致好呢？還是打獵和亂殺好呢？
Piggy!
豬崽子
Sam and Eric! Hey, Sam and Eric.
薩姆埃裏克，薩姆埃裏克
It's me, Ralph.
是我，拉爾夫
When they find me, what are they going to do?
逮住我後他們打算怎麼辦？
Roger sharpened a stick at both ends.
羅傑把一根木棒的兩頭都削尖了
They're going to hurt you tomorrow.
他們明兒要追捕你
We've got to give signals like this -
我們要像這樣發信號
Only louder, of course.
當然，聲音要響些
You've got to go now, Ralph.
你必須馬上走，拉爾夫
Won't you come with me?
你們願不願意跟我一塊兒走
The three of us would have a better chance.
咱們三個會更有希望的
Quick, Ralph!
快，拉爾夫
I'll be in that thicket there. They won't think to look so close.
我就在那兒的灌木叢裏， 他們絕不會想到去查這麼近的地方
- Who is it? Who's there? - Attention!
- 是誰？誰在那兒？ - 立正
- Eric, it's Roger. - Scouts' report.
- 埃裏克，是羅傑 - 偵查兵報告
Here. Take this.
來，拿著這個
Attention!
立正
Scouts' report.
偵查兵報告
Come here.
來這裏
Got Piggy's specs? I'll start a fire.
取豬崽子的眼鏡，我要放一把火
He must be in here somewhere.
他一定躲在什麼地方
You go round that way. We'll smoke him out.
你這樣繞著放火，他就會被煙熏出來
Shh. Something's moved.
噓，什麼在動
Roger, come help.
羅傑，過來幫忙
Got the stick?
拿上棍子？
I told you. He's dangerous.
我告訴過你們，他是個危險的傢伙
Kill the pig! Slit her throat! Bash her in!
殺野豬喲！割喉嚨喲！狠狠揍喲！
Kill the pig! Slit her throat!
殺野豬喲！割喉嚨喲！